# Ali RajabNezhad

# Software Engineer

AliRn1997@gmail.com \ +989037853055 \ GitHub.com/AliRn76 \ in LinkedIn.com/in/AliRn76

## **SUMMARY**

Backend-focused Software Engineer with +8 years of experience in Python and Go. Creator of Panther, a Python web framework focused on performance and simplicity, with 160K+ downloads. Experienced in building scalable systems, performance tuning, and leading development teams.

#### **SKILLS**

Languages & Frameworks: Python | Go | Django | FastAPI | Gin

**Databases:** PostgreSQL | MongoDB | Redis

Monitoring & Logging: Grafana | Prometheus | Loki | FluentBit | Promtail

Infrastructure & DevOps: Docker | Kubernetes | Swarm | Ansible | GitHub Actions | GitLab CI | AWS S3

| NginX | Traefik | Vagrant | Linux | Git

Messaging & Data Pipelines: RabbitMQ | Kafka | Celery | Spark | WebSocket

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer, Yektanet @

05/2024 - present

- Built a **Frequency Cap system** to control ad exposure
- Optimized its performance using A/B testing insights
- Set up a dedicated Redis Cluster for Frequency Cap data
- Extracted financial reports from HDFS using Airflow DAGs
- Migrated legacy CRM with near-zero downtime
- Implemented a **Push Notification** service for 250K+ users
- Refactored slow database queries, significantly **improving performance**

**Open Source Maintainer,** Panther Web Framework @

11/2023 - 05/2024

- Developed a fast Python web framework (Top 3 on TechEmpower benchmarks)
- Reached +160,000 downloads (pepy.tech)
- Wrote documentation, managed GitHub releases

Software Engineer, Digikala Group &

12/2022 - 11/2023

- Built database replication systems for high availability
- Designed a **promotions engine** for complex discount scenarios
- Integrated multiple third-party APIs for logistics and payments

**Software Engineer,** Hamrahe Aval &

01/2022 - 12/2022

- Built a national **Learning Management System** (Shad.ir)
- Developed an S3-compatible object storage system (similar to MinIO)
- Created **bot management** tool, "Bot Father" on Rubika (37M+ users)

Backend Team Lead, ReVision

01/2020 - 12/2021

- Led backend teams for products including Sandbad, ReVPN, ReMenu, and Podingo
- Managed cross-functional team in a fast-paced startup environment

### Freelance Developer

2018 - 01/2020

• Delivered various **full-stack solutions** (HiCoffee, SportHub, etc.)

EDUCATION	
PhD Candidate in Computer Engineering (System Architecture), Islamic Azad University - Tehran North Branch	2024 – present
MS in Computer Engineering (Software), Islamic Azad University - Tehran West Branch	2021 - 2023
BS in Computer Engineering, Islamic Azad University - Tehran North Branch	2016 - 2021